Uh, here's the thing. I I feel like I'm
a reasonably intelligent human being.
Um, and I'd say it probably took me
about 6 years to realize that Will I Am
[laughter]
was just William with dots in it. Anyone
else have that same I feel like half of
you right now are like, "Oh my god, it's
William with dots in it." It's the
little things we miss, you know? It's
just the other day it took again this
same thing for me. The other day, Flow
Rider,
I don't know, maybe I finally saw it
written out. I was like, "Oh my god,
it's Florida with a space in the
middle." I was like, I bet that's where
he's from.
I uh I love reading reviews on the
internet. It's funny now like you type
anything into Google and reviews pop up,
you know, like hotel, right? You type
your friend Kevin into Google and it's
like Kevin three stars
and you're like who's reviewing Kevin?
Also, maybe I shouldn't hang out with
Kevin anymore. Just this shitty
threestar friend. I don't need that. And
there were all these angry onestar
reviews. And then I started looking
through reviews on Yelp of things. And
now I honestly feel that if you hate a
place, I think the worst review you can
give it is two stars.
If you give something one star, that's
about you.
Look at any onestar review. It is
unrelated to the business they're
reviewing.
It's like, I was eating at Cafe Honduras
and that's where I found out my cat had
committed suicide. One star.
Like a hotel. It's like, I called up
this so-called hotel. They told me a
room there was $300.
Do you think I can afford a $300 hotel
room? Do you know how many times I've
been divorced?
Photos of the lobby look pretty cool.
One star.
I went to get my haircut the other day
and I typed in this barber shop and this
was the review that came up. One star
review. all caps. It just said, "I have
never been to this barber shop and I am
never going."
I was like, "Cool, keep us posted."
My frustration, my deep frustration in
my life is with my computer.
Um, it was my understanding that
computers were invented to improve our
lives, to solve problems. What I don't
understand then is why my computer comes
to me once a week and asks if it can
upgrade itself.
Have you had that? He's like, "Hey, can
I fix my own stuff?" I'm like, "I don't
know, dude. Do it on your own [\h__\h]
time." How about just whenever I open
you up, you work? How about that? Can we
make that arrangement? Cuz your computer
won't just be like, "Okay, yeah, I'll do
it." It'll be like, "When do you want to
talk about this again?" It asks you
when. It wants to schedule a [\h__\h]
appointment with you. And it gives you
options, right? It's like, when's good
for you, Colin? How about half an hour
from now? What about an hour from now?
What about later tonight? What about
tomorrow morning? What about in a
fortnight? When works for you? And then
your computer knows how annoying it's
being because the last option just says
later.
Like you're fighting with your friend.
You're like, "I don't know, dude. We're
going to figure it out [\h__\h] later. I
don't know." And then your computer is
passive aggressive, right? You ever on
the the internet? You're just like
surfing the internet. Then a window pops
up. Would you like to upgrade your Adobe
Flash Player?
And you're like, "Um, no, not really. I
uh don't really care about it at all.
Um, it could live or die and it would
not impact my life. I do not care." And
then your computer's like, "Okay, yeah,
no problem. You don't have to upgrade
it. No problem at all. Um, if you don't,
you won't be able to watch videos on the
internet.
Huge problem. Why don't we just go ahead
and upgrade it?" How much does the
upgrade cost? It's free. Why are we
having this conversation?
Then you're like, "Good. Let's do it. Go
ahead." Your computer's like, "Fine."
There's a beat. Another window pops up.
Do you trust it?
I'm like, "I'm sorry. Do I trust what?"
The Adobe Flash upgrade. Do you trust
it? I'M LIKE, YOU JUST [\h__\h]
INTRODUCED IT TO ME.
HEY, what's up?
Are you guys mad at me? Uh, a little bit
about myself. I am bluish. I am black
and Jewish. Uh, [snorts]
black and Jewish. Black and Jewish.
Black and Jewish. Black and Jewish. So,
you at the crossroads.
[laughter]
My dad looks like Arthur Ash and my mom
looks like Howard Stern.
[laughter] Anyway, that's why I look
like Jar Jar Banks.
Uh, I went to a music school in Boston
called Berkeley College of Waste Your
Money Music. [applause] Thank you.
That's the dean of the college.
Uh, I went there because when uh I was
18 years old, society was like, "What do
you want to do with your life?" And I
was like, "Play baselines, my man. What
the [\h__\h] you think?
And then my college was like, "Great.
That'll be $120,000.
I'm actually not too into football. I'm
more into basketball. I love B. I was
watching this um this documentary on the
NBA. Uh it was called The Golden Years
of the NBA." And they're they're
interviewing Magic Johnson and Michael
Jordan. And then they would cut to Bob
Koozie who was like an all-star
basketball player but back in like 19
Dicky6.
And uh now he's just like this shriveled
up old white guy. And uh it kept
throwing me off. Uh cuz all of his
stories about basketball were like
completely irrelevant. He was just like,
"Yeah, I remember when you used to be
able to bring your own sandwiches to the
games. [applause]
You had like a mayonnaise sandwich or a
uh a mustard sandwich. It was the
depression.
And uh one time I was standing at the
one point line and [clears throat] I
could barely breathe cuz all the players
were chain smoking cigarettes.
Next thing you know, I look up in the
stands, wouldn't you know it, Jed Gahoo
is fingering my wife in the mouth. It's
just like ye.
Uh it's very exciting. Americans can go
to Cuba now. you guys have been able to
go forever. Uh, but it's very exciting
to us. So, I went to Cuba and I bought
this souvenir in Cuba because it is the
worst English translation I have ever
seen in my entire life. And it reads,
"If you enter to our kitchen and the she
finds it dirty, it is because the one
that not scrubs this and the one that
this it is not the one that scrubs
and as you he won't scrub. Don't
criticize as this.
[cheering and applause]
Don't criticize as this.
[applause]
It works in every language.
I like to think that the translator like
had a stroke and set Google Translate to
Shakespearean English
and his boss is just like, "YOU GOT TO
GET THIS [\h__\h] ON THE SHELVES,
[screaming] JULIO." NOW, HE'S LIKE, "OH,
[\h__\h] DAMN IT.
If you enter and the she finds it
dirty." I like to think that this is the
first draft of the TLC song Scrubs.
>> [laughter]
>> Like T-Bos wrote it in a rush and Chile
and Left Eye were like, "Yo, what the
[\h__\h] We just won a Grammy for
waterfalls and you're giving us this
[\h__\h] T-Bos.
It is because the one that not scrubs
this and the one that this it is not the
one that scrubs." And as you he WON'T
SCRUB. NO, I DON'T HAVE IT YET. DAMN IT.
Next time I have an audition and the
casting director's like, "You can bring
in your own monologue or scene from your
favorite movie to perform." I just want
to bring this in and put it in her lap
and just be like, "Yeah, that's my head
shot at the top."
And just do the [\h__\h] dialogue off of
this as if it's the dramatic performance
of a lifetime. If you enter to our
kitchen and the she finds it dirty, it
is because the one that not scrubs this
and the one that this it is not the one
that SCRUBS
AND AS YOU HE WON'T SCRUB. DON'T
[screaming] CRITICIZE AS THIS.
[applause]
[cheering]
don't you dare criticize us. [laughter]
And she'll be like, great, you booked
it. You're a dead body on Law and Order.
You guys have been awesome. Enjoy the
rest of the show. I've been taking
CrossFit.
[laughter]
And judging by your reaction, you all
hate CrossFit.
[laughter]
You're like, "Screw that. It's a cult.
I'll tell you what it is. It's a cult."
But here's the thing. I was like 90 lbs
heavier than I am now and I lost a ton
of weight doing it and I love it. Now,
if you don't know what CrossFit is,
CrossFit is the workout craze just
sweeping the nation. Now, here's what
you do. You pay to go to a gym to hit
tires with sledgehammers.
You pull ropes. You push sleds. You
carry heavy buckets from one end of a
gym to the other. But the irony of it is
not lost on me because if you think
about it, it's not bluellar people that
like CrossFit, it's white collar people
that like CrossFit. So basically, white
collar people are paying to simulate
work that they themselves would never be
[\h__\h] caught dead doing. [applause]
Is that amazing?
I love that idea. [applause]
Every time they talk about building a
new transit system in a city, they're
always arguing about, "Oh, it's going to
cost $80 million and raise tax
revenues." No, IT DOESN'T HAVE TO. I got
a way you can build every train system
in the United States and Canada and make
a little money at it. Just tell suburban
white women it's a workout program and
charge them 99 bucks a month to build
the freaking thing for you. They're
already doing it anyway, right? Plus,
how awesome would it be driving out to
your local airport and looking off in a
field and seeing a gaggle of cougars and
yoga pants with pickaxes all just
breaking the ground while they're doing
it. You got a house DJ about 10 paces
behind them spinning dubstep while
they're doing it. [laughter]
Got a trainer. ALL RIGHT, LADIES.
WE NEED TO GET THESE TRACKS AROUND. I
apologize. I misspoke. We need to get
these reps done by 4:30 this afternoon.
Wait a second, Reuben.
You didn't just say tracks, did you? I
told you I will not be part of any real
progress when I work out. No, no, no. I
do not do manual labor. [laughter]
I think you should all work out and eat
right. I think everybody should. And not
because you're going to be a better
person. I don't work out and eat right.
You're not even gonna live longer. I'm
gonna die way before most of you. I grew
up in Maine, which is an epic [\h__\h] hole.
And I grew up on a diet of Appalachian
nutritional failure. All the My family
used to eat Boston market twice a week.
That's disgusting. Rotisserie chickens
are just white trash lobster. That's all
they are. And they're for poor people.
Chickens are peasant food. They are. And
if you don't think that chickens are for
poor people, ask yourself why there's a
bone inside of it for making wishes on.
Ask yourself that.
[applause]
Do you think that rich people came up
with the wishbone? [laughter]
No. That's smacks of Denzian poverty
right there. No, no, no. Rich people
don't wish. They use their vast
resources to make their dreams come
true. No, my friends. IT'S POOR PEOPLE
THAT WISH ON BONES.
NO, GUYS, I think you should eat right
and work out for one reason. The same
reason I do, which is that I don't want
to die gracefully.
I'm tired of everybody saying they want
to go out gracefully. Don't. Everybody's
always like, I want to go out in at my
house with my family around me. And when
I die, I want my soul to pass through
like a wisp of smoke through an open
window.
[snorts]
[laughter]
Not this guy. I want to go out like a
pony caught in a revolving door. That's
how I want to go out. I want to spit my
last breath. I want to go out in an
emergency room with a clump of nurse's
hair in either hand, SCREAMING AT THE
TOP OF MY LUNGS. IF I GO OUT, I'M TAKING
A COUPLE OF YOU [\h__\h] WITH ME. WOO.
[screaming]
AND THEY'RE GOING TO BE LIKE, "WHAT THE
HELL IS HE TALKING ABOUT?" AND THEY'RE
GOING TO LOOK OVER AT THE DOCTOR AND BE
LIKE, "HE CAN'T DO THAT, CAN HE?" AND
I'LL BE LIKE, "DON'T YOU LOOK AT HIM.
HIS DIPLOMAS MEAN NOTHING WHERE WE'RE
GOING. I'VE BEEN TALKING TO THE DARK
OVERLORD AND HE SAID, "WHATEVER I'M
HOLDING ON TO, I CAN BRING TO THE OTHER
SIDE." AND [laughter] THEY'RE GOING TO
BE LIKE, "OH MY GOD." [screaming]
AND THEN RIGHT AT THAT POINT, A BUDDY OF
MINE IS GOING to hijack a nurses station
and he's going to shut off all the
lights on the ward and he's going to
start cranking death metal through the
all call pager and they're going
[laughter] TO BE LIKE, "WHAT THE HELL IS
THAT?" [screaming] AND I'LL BE LIKE,
"THAT'S THE SIGN." AND I'LL, "COME ON,
YOU JUST SHUT YOUR MOUTH." AND I'LL PULL
THEM IN. AND THEN RIGHT AT THE LAST
MINUTE,
[laughter]
I'll flatline,
you know, and uh
you know, and I just figure I could pull
that off if I'm in better shape.
[applause]
You guys have been awesome. My name's
Ben Roy. [cheering] Thank you very much.
I'm excited to be here. [applause]
I didn't really enjoy the World Cup that
much. I tried to get into it. I ain't
like the highlights, but people call
soccer the beautiful game, but that if
you that's if you think jogging is
beautiful.
IT'S A LOT OF JOGGING IN SOCCER. I KNEW
HOW TO FIX SOCCER AND MAKE IT MORE
EXCITING. You just got to put an extra
ball on the field. That's it. [laughter]
You put extra ball on the field, you
fix. It's exciting. Two games going on
at the same time. It's chaos. [laughter]
BE PURE CHAOS. YOU KNOW HOW CHAOTIC it
gets when they drop the extra ball in
the pinball machine and you get
[laughter]
not a not a soccer fan. Uh not a not a
baseball fan. A BASEBALL GAME IS GOOD TO
GO TO IF you got a friend you haven't
seen in 8 years and you want to go
somewhere and talk for a few hours
without interruption. LET'S GO TO THIS
BASEBALL GAME AND CATCH UP. NOTHING'S
HAPPENING.
We can just talk and talk and talk.
Baseball sucks. One of the greatest
achievements in the game of baseball is
the no hitter. That's when nothing
happens. Oh, he was so good. Nothing
happened, man. [laughter]
You know how hard it is to make nothing
happen in this stadium?
Pitchers can just avoid their problems.
If somebody's too good, you can
intentionally walk somebody like, "No,
he's too good. Catcher, stand up a
little bit. stand over there. All right.
Going to throw to you for a few things.
[laughter] No, that dude's too good. I
watched his highlights the other day. He
might knock it out of the park. I don't
want to throw to him. In basketball, if
somebody's too good, you have to put two
players on. YOU GOT TO DOUBLE TEAM HIM.
YOU TWO GUARD HIM. WHICH DUDE, COACH?
The guy with all the commercials and
[\h__\h]
[laughter]
All the parks aren't the same size in
baseball,
which is crazy to me.
Wrigley Field is a different size than
Yankee Stadium, which means it's
different to hit a home run in Wrigley
than Yankee. That's how they score
points and it's different everywhere.
That's crazy. You imagine they did that
in any other sport. Like, man, you I
love playing the Knicks cuz the rims at
Madison Square Garden are 4 in lower
than everybody else. You could just
dunk. I can I never can dunk. It's
harder to dunk in LA than New York.
It's way easier to get a touchdown at
Packer Stadium.
The field IS ONLY 50 YARDS LONG.
Not a big baseball fan. I'm a huge fan
of steroids, though.
Big fan of steroids. I love steroids.
I'm flattered when athletes do steroids.
Flattered. Thank you. Thank you for
sacrificing your long-term health for my
short-term entertainment. Hell yeah.
Thank you so much.
A lot of times they found out late when
athletes were on steroids, especially
baseball play. We just found out you
were on steroids during a 2009 season.
Let it go. IT'S BEEN YEARS. LET IT GO.
What are you going to do? It's over. Cuz
you know what? That person was on drugs.
They were probably hitting home runs,
creating happiness, making people
high-five each other. Like Sammy Sa was
on steroids playing for the Cubs. He was
hitting home runs. You know who was in
the stands watching them? Probably a
father and a son. And they remember
that, "Dad, remember when Sammy Sosa hit
three home runs in one game?" Yeah, I
remember that, son. That was your first
baseball game. Oh, wow. That was an
amazing experience, Dad. It was great
for me to share that experience with
you, too. I love you, Dad. I love you,
too, son.
[laughter]
Steroids did that [\h__\h]
[applause]
Steroids created that beautiful moment
for that father and son. So if you're
against steroids, you're against family
is what I'm saying.
Because PCP never did that for a father
and son. I've never been a father.
REMEMBER, DAD, REMEMBER WHEN THAT NAKED
MAN KEPT PUNCHING US? OH, WHAT A
HORRIBLE NIGHT, DADDY. YEAH, HE HAD SO
MANY COMBINATIONS AND IT FELT LIKE HE
HAD EQUAL POWER IN BOTH HANDS.
[laughter]
Sometimes they found out Olympic
athletes were on steroids. We just found
out you were on steroids during the 2012
Olympics. So that race that you won back
then, you lost it now. Then you we know
that you won then, but now you lost. So
second place they lost back then they
won now then
and you lost. So now that you lost back
then now give us your gold medals back.
[laughter]
You can say that I lost. You can shame
me in the press all that but you
wouldn't be able to get my gold medals.
I'd make UP LIKE THE GOLD MEDALS. Oh
man, I don't the go I don't even have
those medals anymore, man. What happened
to the med? OH DUDE, I GOT DRUNK AND I
JUST STARTED GIVING THEM TO LITTLE KIDS
IN CANCUN. MAN, I WAS SO DRUNK AND THEY
WAS SELLING CHICKLETS SAYING IT WAS 1:00
IN THE MORNING AND LIKE THEY WERE THE
REAL CHAMPIONS. I gave them the gold
medals. [laughter]
Well, Lance Armstrong Lance Armstrong
was on drugs. Well, WHO GIVES A [\h__\h]
HE'S RIDING A BIKE. LET HIM RIDE HIS
BIKE. LET THAT BOY DO DRUGS AND RIDE HIS
BIKE. STOP BOTHERING THAT BOY.
[applause]
And also, LANCE ARMSTRONG WAS ABLE TO
BECOME a millionaire riding a bicycle.
He's a goddamn magician in my eyes. He's
a legend AND A MAGICIAN. HOW DID HE DO
THAT? HOW'D HE DO THAT? [applause]
How do you make any money riding a bike
if you don't have a sandwich or a piece
of you delivering to somebody with you?
So, let that boy ride his bike. HE'S A
MAGICIAN. ALSO, OF COURSE, HE WAS ON
DRUGS. YOU SEE HOW LONG HE HAD TO RIDE A
BIKE FOR? I TAKE AN ADDERALL JUST TO
CLEAN MY APARTMENT. And even then, I
DON'T FINISH. I JUST END UP REALLY
FOCUSED on some weird [\h__\h] from my past.
My high school yearbook. Damn, I miss my
friend Ken. Oh, my friend Tori, MY
FRIEND BLACK. OH, IT'S SCOOP. OH, LOOK,
DEBATE TEAM, FOOTBALL TEAM. MISS
CARTER'S ENGLISH CLASS. DAMN, THIS PLACE
IS A MESS.
[applause]
Thank you. Good evening. How are you?
Some of you didn't applaud, but that's
all right. [laughter]
>> It's very well lit in here. I can see
who applauded.
took a vacation, went to Guatemala,
saw some beautiful stuff there I'd never
seen before. Saw a volcano for the first
time. That was beautiful. What else they
see? Oh, guys riding mopeds down rocky
roads, steering with just one hand
because they're holding a baby with the
other.
Saw that so many times it stopped
bothering me.
First time you see like, "Oh my god,
look at that lunatic riding a moped
holding a baby. Second time you see
you're like, "Oh my god, what a crazy
coincidence. [laughter]
For only the second time in my entire
life and within 5 seconds of the first
time, [laughter]
I'm seeing a guy riding a moped holding
a baby." Third time you see, you're
like, "Wow, so many cute babies in
Guatemala."
And then you rent a moped [laughter]
and you know where you take it. Yes, the
adoption agency. [laughter] Then you're
like, "Oh, yeah. I get it. It's about
living on the edge. [laughter]
It's about making a baby live on the
edge while I'm relatively safe."
[laughter]
Went to the doctor. My shoulder was
hurting me. My regular doctor goes, "I'm
going to send you to a sports medicine
doctor." I was like, "Yeah, that's a
good call. It's definitely been 6 months
since my last sports medicine checkup.
>> [laughter]
>> I am due.
Guy looked at my shoulder like, "Oh
yeah, that's an inflamed rotator cuff.
That's a thrower's injury."
I bet it is sometimes.
[laughter]
Think it also might be a reaching for a
box of animal crackers
at 5:30 in the morning injury
or perhaps a moving a lightweight jacket
just a bit too quickly
into an overhead compartment injury. But
what do I know? I'm not a sports
medicine doctor. Could be from the last
time I threw anything. Little League
1979.
Pitched 10 no hitters that season.
could have joined the pros, chose comedy
instead.
>> You're welcome.
[applause]
Saw a doctor on TV talking about how to
work exercise into your daily life
without going to the gym. He had an
interesting suggestion. He's like, "We
all make three phone calls a day, right?
They last 10 minutes each. Just walk
around.
Why are you making these phone calls?
That's 30 minutes of exercise every day.
I was like, I haven't made three phone
calls in the past year and a half.
They don't last 10 minutes each, but I
don't want to go to the gym. So, I will
give this a whirl.
Start calling people up. Taking a little
walk. Hello. Uh, Hunan Palace.
[laughter]
I was wondering what kind of food you
specialize in.
Oh, it is Chinese food. Okay.
No need to yell. [laughter]
So, what time are you open till? Oh, is
it fun being open till 10:00?
If you couldn't be open till 10:00, when
would you be open to? [laughter]
No, this is not a prank call.
I'm working out. [laughter]
And I got to say, not really feeling a
burn yet. Need you to hang tight for
another 8 and 1/2 minutes
because I have more questions.
>> [laughter]
>> All right. You're stranded on a desert
island.
You can only bring one Cheryl Crow
album.
Yes. Greatest hits is the right answer.
I've never dropped my phone in the
toilet. That's a good thing.
Someone tells me they dropped their
phone in a toilet. Their next sentence
has to be, "So, of course, I left it in
the toilet
because it wouldn't even occur to me to
reach my hand into a toilet to avoid
buying a new phone." Some people say,
"But I put in a bowl of dry rice after."
Oh, the way a surgeon preps his
scalpels.
[laughter]
Think I saw a show about that on the
Discovery Channel. It's called Uncooked
Rice, [laughter]
Nature's Disinfectants.
>> [laughter]
>> I asked this woman if she ever dropped
her phone on toilet. She goes, "I did,
but there was no pee in there.
Really? Never."
[laughter]
That is the luckiest series of events
ever.
They're installing a new toilet. You're
first in line.
Mayor cuts the ribbon. [laughter]
The glare from his scissors blinds you.
You slip. You fall. You drop that phone.
Where's it end up? Ah, the crystal clear
waters
of an innocent virgin toilet. Thank you
everybody. Good night.
Just to put you guys at ease, this is
not the worst show I've ever done.
That would have been about 6 months ago.
I performed at San Quinton State
Penitentiary
uh in America. In America, prisons are
different than they are in Canada and
that we have way more of them and we put
everyone in them.
But San Quinton is just for murderers
basically. You might be wondering,
Anthony, how did you get in that
situation? Well, I drink
and I'm friends with a lot of musicians.
So, I'm doing a show and afterwards I'm
drinking with a band, a band called
Queens of the Stone Age. Very famous.
Yes. One of the best rock bands of all
time. And I'm talking about their tour
and they say, "Oh, we're almost done. We
just got to do a couple couple more
shows and then we're going doing one
show at San Quinton State Penitentiary."
And I'm just drunk enough
to say, "Do you need an opener?
I'm like, "Yeah, that would be great.
Please come and do the show with us. I'm
very excited." Couple weeks later, they
get back to me. They say, "Anthony, the
prison has approved you to open for us."
Which I could not believe.
And then I get a list of the rules of
what I'm not allowed to talk about on
stage at San Quentin. And it says no
swearing, no religion, no sex, no
controversy, nothing that will rile up
the inmates. Basically, it's my set list
with the word no written in front of
everything.
So, I call the band and I say, "Guys, I
don't think I can do this. I can't
follow these rules. I literally cannot
follow these rules." and they say, "It
doesn't matter, Anthony. Whatever you do
is cool with us. If you go on stage and
they cut your mic immediately, that's
even better. That's even cooler. We
think it's a good story." That's all I
need to hear.
So, I fly over to the prison with the
band. We drive into the prison. We get
out and again, everyone is a murderer.
And it's not a prison like everyone's
behind bars. It's like a college campus
where murderers are just walking around
freely
as if they have somewhere to be.
I'm trying not to pay any attention. I'm
just hanging with a band back in the
corner. It's about 10 minutes before
showtime and all of a sudden I look up
and there's four guys surrounding me
holding shotguns.
They work there,
but they're looking at me like I'm about
to try to escape.
And then another guy walks up, gets
right in front of me, goes, "Anthony,
I'm the warden here at San Quinton State
Penitentiary."
And I say, "Nice to meet you." He
doesn't look like it's nice to meet me.
He says, "Anthony, music is one thing,
but comedy with prisoners like this, ah,
I don't know. We just watched some of
your stuff on YouTube. It's offensive,
which is what makes it funny. You're my
favorite comedian,
but with these guys, I don't know. It
could go sideways.
And I realize he's trying to get me to
step down
to say I'm not going to perform if it's
going to be a problem, which would have
been fine a couple hours before I got in
a [\h__\h] flight.
So I say, "Warden, listen. I've had
things go sideways all the time.
Not a problem for me. What do you want
me to do? You want me to do less time?
What should I not talk about? And he
goes, "Ah, I just don't know. I don't
know that stuff on YouTube." And I feel
like, you know what? I'm a professional
comedian. I can diffuse this with my
sense of humor.
So, I say, "Warden, if the problem is
the stuff you saw on YouTube, don't
worry. this is going to be all new
material.
They don't laugh at all.
One of the guys [\h__\h] his shotgun.
So the warden says, "All right, let me
take give you a tour. Let me walk you
around." And this beautiful 27year-old
redhead girl comes and joins us on the
tour. The warden turns to us proudly and
says, "This is my daughter.
this place is so safe because of me. I
can bring my daughter to come watch the
show. I'm thinking, you can bring your
daughter,
but I can't tell a joke.
So, I pull the warden aside and I say,
"Listen, the show starts in 5 minutes.
Let me be a part of this evening. Let me
just go on stage and introduce the band
and then I'll leave." The warden shakes
my hand and says, "Thank you. I'd
appreciate it." Keep in mind that is not
what I am going to do.
So the show's about to start. I'm
standing in the wings with the band and
the band's trying to reassure me.
They're like, "Anthony, don't worry. Do
whatever you want. We're cool."
Okay.
This old lady gets on stage. She works
for the prison. And she says, "I want to
thank everyone. I want to thank the crew
for putting this together.
And now she turns and looks me right in
the eyes. Says, "And now, a very nice
young man,
Anthony."
Now, I don't know if you've ever
performed in a prison before,
but that is the worst way you can be
introduced.
I walk onto the stage with 200 murderers
whistling at me.
I take the microphone and I say,
"Listen, my name is Anthony Jesselnik.
I've been doing this for 17 years. I'm a
famous comedian. So, if you haven't
heard of me, you must have done
something pretty [\h__\h] up.
>> [applause]
>> The place goes crazy.
That's exactly the joke they wanted to
hear.
My mic gets cut off immediately.
[applause]
I drop the mic to the ground. I'm about
to introduce the band. And then I look
out into the audience and I see the
warden standing in the back with his
arms crossed and his daughter standing
next to him.
and I can't resist.
So I say, and I want to thank the warden
for bringing us his daughter.
At this point,
you could hear a pin drop.
Even the prisoners are like, "We killed
the guy,
but we're not crazy.
Thank God he's leaving after this.
I introduce the band. The band walks on
stage like, "We should not have told you
to do whatever you want."
They go up, they start playing. They're
amazing. Someone taps me in the
shoulder. I turn around, they go,
"Anthony, the warden wants to know if
you'd like to go watch the show with
him."
>> I'm not following for that.
I say, "I'm good right here.
The show ends. The band gets off stage.
They go, "Let's get the hell out of here
right now." I agree.
We go to run into the van and someone
grabs my arm. I turn around and it's the
warden.
It's very seriously. He goes, "Anthony,
I just want to say that next time you
come to town, my wife and I are going to
have to come out and see you." And I
said, 'Warden,
the next time you see me, I'll be
humiliating you on television.
YES. HOW WE GOING, FOLKS? WE ALL GOOD?
>> AH, YES. I love Montreal. You people
like sports. I like sports. We've got so
much in common.
You know, my favorite spectator sport, Q
rage. Just watching impatient people
standing in line losing their godamn
minds just
[laughter] I love it. It's the best cuz
there's nothing you can do when you're
standing in line. You either stand in
line or you piss off out of the line.
STANDING THERE GOING, "GOD [screaming]
DAMN IT." IT DOESN'T DO ANYTHING. It's
endlessly entertaining.
My favorite ever ever moment of Q rage.
I was in the supermarket recently and
you know how in the supermarket you can
bip your own [\h__\h]
You know what I'm talking about? How
they let you do your own bloody? Yep.
That's Q. Rage in action right there.
Cuz we got so sick of watching other
people scan our goods. We're like piss
off. Let me do it. That's how you do it.
Look at [laughter] that. See how quick I
am. Oh yeah. I'm getting old here.
Wait wait wait wait.
Fruit. Hang on. Fruit.
Where's the fruit there? Is that a red
delicious or a royal gar? Oh, it's a
pink lady. Oh, that's it's a good price
for this time of year.
Must be on special. Okay, go.
Anyway, I'm standing here. There's a guy
standing in front of me. There's six
selfch checkout machines. Two of them
are broken because two of them are
always broken for some reason. The guy
in front of me has got veins of fury
popping out of his neck BECAUSE BY some
comedy miracle,
the four people using the remaining
selfch checkckout machines had never
done it before.
How does that even happen? We've had
them for like 10 years. I was giggling
like an idiot. The guy in front of me
was having a stroke
while simultaneously four people all
just stood there going.
[applause]
And the guy in front of ME WAS LIKE,
"OH, THIS IS [\h__\h]
TURNING AROUND TO ME TO try and absorb
me into his bubble OF HATRED. CAN YOU
BELIEVE THIS [\h__\h] LIKE, it's the
greatest injustice he's ever
encountered. Like, doctors without
borders ran out of antibiotics just
before they got to HIS VILLAGE. OH,
WE'RE ALL GOING [screaming] TO DIE.
IT'S a supermarket cue, you ball sack.
Relax.
It was a long flight on the way over
here. Uh, Jimel jetlagged. Am I saying
that right? I um I did have a good time
though. I managed to watch quite a lot
of inflight entertainment. Watched my
favorite show uh mentally deranged
hoarders. You guys seen THAT ONE? AH,
SUCH a good show. Although I think maybe
we need to lay off hoarders. Okay. I
think maybe there's one too many
television programs exposing the horrors
of people that enjoy collecting [\h__\h]
It's their house. Let them DO IT. NO, WE
HAVE TO FIX THEM. NO, you don't. If they
want to climb over a stack of cat [\h__\h]
stained National Geographic magazines
from the 1970s to get to the fridge, let
them.
THEY LIKE IT.
OH, BUT IT'S A MENTAL ILLNESS. YEAH.
WELL, MAYBE. But I would argue it's more
insane to film them doing it.
[applause] Yeah.
And then then package it like a tacky
microwave meal for one so [\h__\h] can
sit AT HOME GOING, "LOOK HOW [\h__\h] THAT
PERSON IS. THEY'VE GOT TOO many of the
same thing."
Who's more insane in that scenario? I
ponder.
Montreal, you guys have BEEN AWESOME.
ENJOY THE REST OF YOUR NIGHT. SEE YOU
[music] LATER.
>> Good evening, ladies and gentlemen. I am
uh Paul F. Tommpkins. I live in Los
Angeles, California, and I'd like to
tell you a story about a place in Los
Angeles, California called the Magic
Castle.
The Magic Castle is a private club for
magicians.
This is a true thing that I have just
said to you. Magicians have their own
private club and it's called the Magic
Castle. This is a place where magicians
can go to
not get beat up. Presumably,
the Magic Castle is a more elegant name
than the Magic Fort.
My wife very much wanted to go to the
Magic Castle. We managed to get some
passes. It's very exclusive. Very
exclusive.
We got all dressed up to go, but there
was something I saw there that haunts me
to this day. It was a very strange thing
that I couldn't process immediately. At
the Magic Castle, the walls are covered
floor to ceiling with magical [\h__\h]
There's just props and top hats and
wands all over the place, play bills and
posters just crammed floor to ceiling.
It's too much, frankly. And sometimes
you have to just let your eyes go soft
so you can remember who you are.
And so there's all these portraits of
magicians. Some famous, some not famous.
Magicians from the past, magicians from
the present, none from the future,
because it's the magic castle, not the
science castle.
And at one point, I saw a portrait of
this older gentleman, and I knew
instantly as soon as I saw it, something
is not right about this picture. Paul,
there were real eyes in the eyeholes.
No, there weren't. Opportunity missed,
by the way. Magic Castle. It's just a
regular old painting of this older man.
But I knew looking at it on a cellular
level, something is wrong with this
painting. I stared at it, stared at it,
and then all of a sudden, like a magic
eye drawing, I saw it, and then it was
all I could see. It was a painting of an
old man. This guy was probably in his uh
late 80s, early 90s. From the looks of
his clothing and the frames of his
glasses, it was probably painted in the
late 60s, early 70s. And I'm looking at
this painting and I realize all of a
sudden very clearly that the man in this
painting
is wearing a toupe.
It's a painting.
What kind of a creep artist
sees an old man walk into his studio
wearing a toupe and says, "I paint the
truth, sir."
These brushes will not corroborate that
lie upon your head.
Then the more I thought about it, I
started to get mad at the old man
because why didn't he check? Like
getting your oil portrait done takes a
long time. You have to sit there in the
same place in the same position for
weeks and weeks if not months. It's not
like getting a caricature done at a
carnival like there you go. There's your
oil painting.
You would think at some point halfway
through this process the guy would get
up and like, "Hey, let's have a look.
See how she's coming along. Oh, hey. Uh,
can I talk to you for a second, son? Um,
boy. Look, um I'm not trying to tell you
how to do your job or anything, but uh
could you not make my hair look fake?
Here's why I ask. You see, years from
now, uh decades hence when this uh
portrait is hanging in my guild's hall
of fame, as it were, and uh people who
will have no idea whether I lived or
died uh will see this. This will be the
only proof that I ever walked upon this
planet. Uh, I'd rather these uh these
future people uh in this fleeting
glimpse they get of of me uh rather that
these uh generations yet unborn rather
that when they see this my official oil
portrait uh the first thought not be uh
huh wig. So I tell you what um perhaps
if I make it worth your while I snip you
a few extra $100. Um, perhaps you could
help me achieve an illusion I was unable
to achieve in life.
Ladies and gentlemen, thank you very
much and enjoy the rest of your stay in
Montreal.
I
am
from Ireland.
We are a country
full
of lunatics.
There isn't a person in Ireland who's
more than a FIRST COUSIN AWAY FROM
GENUINE PSYCHIATRIC ILLNESS.
And I love it. There's a man who lives
near me who has the dental equivalent of
a comb over.
He has
no teeth. No teeth on this side of his
mouth and the teeth on this side are
trying to cover it up.
THERE.
THERE WAS A SET OF IDENTICAL TWIN
SISTERS who worked in a shop in the town
and one of them passed away. And about a
week later, my friend went in and said
to the girl, "Was it you or your sister
that died?"
Now,
[applause]
YOU CAN'T BE LOCKING PEOPLE LIKE THIS
UP. THEY NEED TO BE LET FREE TO ROAM
AROUND THE COUNTRYSIDE.
IN IRELAND, BEFORE WE HAD PSYCHIATRIC
HOSPITALS, ALL WE HAD WERE OPEN SPACES.
IF YOU WERE MAD, PEOPLE JUST TOLD YOU TO
[\h__\h] OFF.
>> [applause]
>> You
you spend THE DAY RUNNING AROUND A BIG
FIELD.
YOU COME BACK INTO TOWN AROUND 6:00 FOR
A SANDWICH WITH THE CRUSTS CUT OFF. CUZ
YOU'RE MENTAL.
NEVER GIVE A LUNA TAKE THE HEEL OF A
LOAF OF BREAD. HE'LL TAKE THE EYES OUT
OF YOUR HEAD.
>> AND THEN BACK INTO THE FIELD.
TO SLEEP IN A TREE with some sheep.
I DON'T LIKE SHEEP. I DON'T LIKE THEM.
THEY'RE TOO [\h__\h] VAGUE.
THEY'RE ALL BLURRY AROUND THE EDGES.
WHERE DOES THE SHEEP EVEN BEGIN?
THE BIGGEST FRIGHT I EVER GOT IN MY LIFE
WAS FROM A SHEEP. AND WHEN I SAY SHEEP,
YOU DON'T EVEN KNOW HOW MANY I'M TALKING
ABOUT. THAT'S HOW VAGUE THEY ARE. THERE
COULD HAVE BEEN ONE OR THOUSANDS.
There was one.
I was up a mountain
in the wilderness
AND I FELT AS IF THE wildness
inside me
WAS BEING MIRRORED
BY THE WILDNESS
OUTSIDE OF ME. And I felt at peace. SO I
LET A FEW ROARS OUT OF ME.
I OPENED UP ALL ME CHAKRAS. ME MULADAKRA
SHARK WAS FLAPPING IN THE WIND.
THOSE [\h__\h] OF A [\h__\h] SHEEP
STANDING BEHIND ME.
I DIDN'T SEE HIM, BUT HE WAITED TILL I
WAS AT MY MOST VULNERABLE.
AND HE went me.
[applause]
I DIDN'T RUN. I just wasn't there
anymore.
THERE ARE THINGS THAT HELP and there ARE
THINGS THAT DON'T HELP. YOU CAN'T HAVE
PRETTY WOMEN READING THE NEWS. IT'S TOO
DISTRACTING. HOW ARE YOU SUPPOSED TO
WEEP FOR EGYPT IF SHE'S GORGEOUS WITH
BIG FALSE EYELASHES? WE KNOW THIS IN
IRELAND. WE HAVE A ROUGH LOOKING WOMAN
READING THE NEWS.
SHE'S GOT A BLACK EYE AND THREE MISSING
TEETH.
SHE JUST STARES DOWN THE CAMERA. YOU
THINK YOU HAVE IT BAD? WAIT TILL YOU SEE
THIS FELLA. ROLL THE TAPE.
LOOK.
LOOK AT HIM. HE'S ONLY GOT ONE LEG AND
THEY'RE STILL SHOOTING AT HIM. LOOK.
NOW FOR THE WEATHER. IT'LL BE PISSING
RAIN ALL WEEK.
[applause]
I believe
that [applause]
alcohol
alcohol helps. YOU NEED A DRINK. IRISH
PEOPLE DO. WHEN THINGS ARE GETTING
SERIOUS, IT'S WHEN YOU NEED A DRINK THE
MOST.
It's why we put St. Patrick's Day in the
middle of Lent.
That [applause]
that
THAT WASN'T A FLUKE. THAT'S PURE CELTIC
GENIUS.
WE KNEW THERE WAS NO WAY WE WERE GOING
TO GO 40 days
and 40 nights on pancakes.
We'd need A HALFIME DURING RAMADAN. So
we would
ON ST. PATRICK'S DAY JESUS HIMSELF COMES
OUT OF the desert. Mother of God.
[applause]
[cheering]
Is there any chance of a point? Is there
devil is driving me demented. It's
question after question. He is
relentless who he is. Point of Guinness
for being a Sheamus. Thanks. What's
that? I'd love to judge the parade.
Hello. Good evening. Bonjour. Um, I am
from Britain. Uh, it's true. I love
Montreal. I've had a great time here,
but I'm actually trying not to drink
that much. British people, of course,
have a reputation for it. And I used to
drink a lot before shows. I would
regularly have um maybe half a bottle of
wine before going on stage. And I would
do that religiously. Um, and by
religiously, I mean without really
thinking it through. Uh, so um they're
um Sorry. Yeah. I'm not so sure about
that one. [laughter]
I thank you. [applause]
In some parts of North America, that
would be a dangerous joke, but not here.
I that in fact it was in it was in the
United States that I uh started to think
maybe my drinking is not normal because
uh I doing shows there. None of the
American comedians drink. They were
having milkshakes. They tried to get me
to have a milkshake before the show,
which I couldn't do that because I'm
intolerant. Um
not a lactose intolerance. I just don't
like Americans. Uh so I uh
uh [applause]
I I people often imagine that I consume
nothing at all because I'm obviously so
pathetic looking. There's no stature to
me at all. And ironically, I mean, I'm
always eating. I love food. If somebody
said to me, "Yeah, thank you." Yeah.
Woo! Another food fan is in the house.
Um it's good. Is this really getting
popular? Food is catching on. Uh they
reckon in 10 years everyone will be
having food. Uh
# food if you're interested. Uh yeah, if
someone said to me, "You have to either
give up food or give up sex," I'd say,
"No, I don't." Uh
that would be the end of that
conversation. I think I'm not falling
for that one again, wife. Uh
it's been um [applause]
a nice people. You clap. you you are
such enthusiastic people that the
mention of food makes someone go woo.
Yeah, I uh I really like I like Canada.
It was worth the effort, considerable
effort uh that it took to get into the
country. That's the only thing. Canadian
security is quite suspicious. They
already knew I was a comedian. What was
the purpose of your visit? Business. I
said there's a comedy festival. Their
next question was, "Have you visited a
farm in the last 7 days? And will you be
visiting a farm while you're here?" Yes,
of course. That's all anyone does when
they come here. That's what Montreal's
famous for. How are your shows? I didn't
do any in the end. Just went to farms. I
uh [laughter]
How did you enjoy Canada? It was mostly
just sheep and arable land as far as I
can make that. It's one hell of a
country.
How did it [laughter] compare with the
farms you went to all over the world?
Oh, they're very special, those Canadian
farms.
Uh but yes, it was uh it was worth it. I
think there's a certain amount that we
have in common, the Brits and the
Canadians. A certain kind of uh fairly
lowkey approach to life. Fairly small
things seem to shock the Canadians.
Well, I'm taking um my proof from a a
song three times while I've been here.
I've heard this song which it was a huge
hit in Canada. Uh I'm sure you've heard
it. It's coming out of every building. I
just met you and this is crazy, but
here's my number. Call me maybe. You
know, this song is really repetitive.
It's in my head. Here's my number. Call
me maybe. Is this crazy? Is this what
passes for crazy in Canada?
I would say if you've just met someone
and you like them, uh, trading numbers
is pretty much the least crazy course of
action I can imagine. Really, I think
the song should go, I just met you and
this is pretty solid admin. Really, I
I just met you and this will work out
fine. The song for me would be a lot
more truthful if it said, "Hey, I just
met you and this is crazy. I've written
my name in [\h__\h] on your garage door.
Uh, [applause]
thank you. But
different cultures are obviously
different because at home I didn't get
into the charts with that song.
You've I've enjoyed myself. You've been
a really nice audience. I would have got
through more material. Always leave them
wanting more. That was my uncle's uh one
piece of advice. That's how he lost his
job in uh emergency relief. Um,
thank you. Some of you almost laughed
before the joke there, but you've been
very nice. My name is M Wson. Good.
Thank you.
>> Nice to be here. I'm staying at the
hotel across the way. I got I got room
service last night. What a delight. You
make a phone call. 10 minutes later,
there's a knock at your door. The
sweetest, most polite man. May I come
in? May I come in?
May you come in? I summoned you.
Of
course you may come in enter my lege.
Then he says, "Uh, where would you like
this? Where would you like this?" And I
lie. I lie every time.
So just place it at the desk. You put it
at the desk where I manage my
correspondence.
The desk where I write my letters
sitting upright. That's where I'll eat
my dinner.
One of these times, I'd love to tell the
truth.
Where would you like this? All right,
here's what's going to happen.
I'm going to dive back into the bed and
pull the covers up to my chin. I want
you to delicately place the tray on my
tummy.
And if you feed it to me, you can write
in your own tip.
That's where I would like it.
Why do I have to lie?
I lied on the airplane. I lied to the
flight attendant last night
cuz I wanted the exit row. I'm 6'6.
6'6. That's a lot of Jew.
That's so much Jew. We normally don't
come in this size.
But I wanted the exit row. But when you
take the exit row, they come around and
they deputize you. a hero.
Are you willing and able to help in the
event of an emergency?
No.
No. I am neither willing nor able to
help in the event of an emergency. I I
will lose my mind. Are you kidding me? I
took two Xanax to pack for this flight.
You think I'm going to usher strangers
from smoldering wreckage?
>> No.
I played hockey when I was a when I was
a child. Do you like me now?
>> I did. [applause]
I did. I really wanted to to figure
skate,
but then I I I knew myself that I knew I
would not be able to handle the
scrutiny.
And I realized that figure skating, as
brutal as hockey is, figure skating is
much more brutal, barbaric, even to make
the woman finish skating after she's
fallen.
lowest point in your life. Keep dancing,
sweetie.
Yeah. Try another lutz.
They should race the Zamboni out there,
scoop her up, and whisk her off into a
private room where they give her a
carton of Mal Bros and a pillow to
scream into.
She's not going to win.
It's over. You never see a woman on the
gold medal stand with slush running down
her thigh,
split lip and a bloody nose.
Let her start to regroup.
Instead, they make her finish skating,
give her scores. We know the scores.
Then they interview her.
Don't even give her time to
recombobulate.
She's apologetic.
I'm sorry I'm sorry I'm late. I was just
digging out from under an avalanche of
broken dreams.
Hi, Mom. Hi. Thanks for turning a
carefree hobby into a joyless prison.
I I've never tasted a brownie.
[sighs]
Christina, why do you think you fell?
Maybe because it was so slippery.
Yeah, it was like a sheet of ice out
there. They ought to do something about
that. Maybe throw down some rocks. All
What's next for you, Christina? What's
next? I'm going to see if I can trade in
this bronze medal for my childhood.
THANK YOU.
OH, Messi
full swall.
Uh, how many of you guys were at a long
day of work today? By a round of
applause, who was working?
[applause and cheering] Gosh,
so wonderful that you came out here,
everyone, whether you were working or
not. Uh, I used to work at an ad agency
and, uh, they told us they had access to
everything we did online. So, like you
shouldn't email anything you wouldn't
want the CEO to read. So, that affected
the way I wrote emails, you know? So,
I'd be like, "Hey, Chrissy, did you see
America's Next Top Model last night?
That Tyra Banks is such a [\h__\h] But you
know who isn't a [\h__\h] My boss, Carrie
Peters.
Also, I think that Tyra has really
gained some weight since last season.
But you know who's really slimmed down?
My supervisor, Cindy Gudak.
Oh, man. I got to go. It's 5:30 and I'm
still at work. Unlike Gwen Duchon and
Lissy Billfield who sneak out of work
early every night.
Uh, that wasn't the worst job I ever
had. I used to be the drama instructor
at a kids overnight camp. And you always
get that kid who signs up for drama cuz
she thinks she's a real actress. She's
got that acting voice. So every time
she'd get on stage, she'd be like, "If
you believe in fairies, clamp your
hands. Don't let Tink die.
[laughter]
And it didn't matter what the play was,
you know, she'd be like, "Beware the
odds of March. A soothsayer bids you.
Beware the odds of March." [laughter]
Uh, but you know, in my cabin, I didn't
have like the super, you know, artistic
camper or the athletic camper. I had the
crier. Uh, so she'd come up to me and
she'd be like, "I called BOBBY A NAME,
BUT I WAS JUST KIDDING. AND THEN HE
[screaming] CALLED ME A NAME, BUT HE HE
GET'S
[applause]
changing people.
Uh, I got a problem with customer
service. I don't know what's going on.
People got no passion anymore in their
work. I don't know. I've been working
since I've been eight.
I was watching cartoons in the living
room. My Italian father came in. He's
like, "Hey, go start a business."
Now,
now I had the type of father, he always
questioned my downtime.
I couldn't take a nap, nothing.
He'd always ask me, "Hey, listen. How
long you get for lunch at school? How
long?"
I'm like, "I don't know, about an hour."
He's like, "Well, how long does it take
to eat a sandwich?"
I'm like, "10 minutes." He's like,
"Don't you think for the extra 50 you
could generate some revenue for this
family?"
So, I've been constantly looking for
work. I was an alter boy on Sundays. You
didn't get paid for that, right? But you
could pick up extra shifts during the
week working funerals. Okay?
So, what I would do is I would eat my
lunch at school, run over to the church,
and work a funeral.
All the other kids eating their
sandwich, having fun, meeting other
kids. 12 years old, I'm over a corpse
with incense.
>> [applause]
>> So, I I grew up with having a work ethic
and now I don't see that. Every time I
go, I went to Home Depot looking at a
barbecue, right? Does anybody at Home
Depot know anything about anything in
the store?
[applause]
So, I'm in the barbecue section. a woman
that worked there kind of fell into the
section.
And do you ever look at somebody that
works somewhere and just on the look
alone you're like, they don't know what
the hell they're doing.
But I lobbed one in. I said, "Let me lob
one in, see where she's at."
I said, "Excuse me, you know anything
here
about the Weber?"
She's like, "Uh,
I think this one." I go, "Oh, you're
going to make it up."
[applause]
And I didn't hear a word she said after
that cuz now I'm focused on the full
goatee that she's got. What?
Now, if you're a woman and you want to
grow out a goatee
and work at Home Depot,
fine.
But shouldn't you be in the back on a
forklift or something
[applause]
handling sad?
This is the best they got. This is the
front line of employment.
And if this is what's up front, what the
hell is in the bag?
[applause]
It's an epidemic, man.
I was over at my buddy's house. We were
talking about things, right? I got a
friend. He's got a lot of weapons at the
house. I don't know if you know anybody
like this. Got a lot of weaponry.
He's got a compound bow and arrow in the
house. I go, "Now, if you don't know
what a compound bow is, the arrow
travels at about a 100red yards per
second. It could take out a timberwolf,
no problem." Right. I'm like, "John,
what the hell you got this in the house
for?" He's like, "You kidding me?
[laughter]
It's for home invasion."
Home invasion.
Could you imagine the poor bastard
that breaks into my buddy's house?
As a criminal, you can't even prepare
for something like that,
right? The criminal comes through the
kitchen window.
He thinks nobody's home.
My buddy hears him. He gets out his bow
and arrow.
[applause]
Criminals in the living room. Suspects
nothing. Right. Then out of nowhere,
do you know how that screws up your
mind?
You got to look down and process. I got
an arrow hanging out of my chest right
now.
Did I break into an Apaches home?
Are there Indians here? Is this a
casino? WHAT THE HELL'S GOING ON?
You guys have been great. Take care. Be
good.
>> ALL RIGHT, EVERYONE. THANKS. Calm down.
Yeah. Oh,
well, it's good to be here. Um, I do
voices and stuff. Uh, this one's mine,
though. This one's not a joke. I hear
it, too.
I was I was taking a shower the other
day and I was talking to myself and I
realized, darn it, I'll never be able to
play that sexy chick in scary movies and
the shower scene when the killer's about
to kill her cuz she always has a really
hot voice. You know, like the killer
walks in just,
"Hello, who is it? Who's there?"
>> Done. That's a knife. But I think if a
killer heard my voice in the shower, I
really think he'd just be weirded out.
And he just walks in just, "Hello, who's
there? [laughter] How's your day going?"
Huh? Oh, man. Yeah.
He'd be like, "Never mind. This is
weird. I'm going home.
Come back. I got bubbles." [laughter]
Oh jeez. I used to work at Forever 21, a
girl's retail store. And I would take
good care of my zone of clothes. I
folded everything. Nothing was on the
floor. Then I got girls that would run
and they're like, "This is a dumb shirt.
Throw it." Good catch, Tiffany.
[laughter] Swim in the clothes. Yeah.
Stop it. They're not bubbles. Stop.
But when I was in an angry mood, I can
always count on my Japanese girls to
walk in the door and brighten my day in
an instant. Have you ever seen a pack of
Japanese girls and their friends? Man,
they're like a little cartoon. It they
just get so excited about stuff they'd
run there.
>> Look at this scrunchie. You're so cute.
Let's walk by one together. You're my
best friend. [laughter]
Wow, life is beautiful. Thanks, Japanese
girls. Thanks.
I wrote that song.
That's what I need. Some Japanese
friends, huh? That'd be nice. If I'm
ever feeling sad, just call one up. Hey,
[snorts] you there? Hello, kitty. Yeah,
thanks. Great.
I also really want black lady friends in
my life. Man, that'd be the best. They
make everything sound so exciting.
One time I was in an elevator with a
couple black ladies and all this one
lady said was, "Yeah, let's go do that."
I was like, "Oh yeah, let me follow.
That sounds fun." Yeah.
[laughter]
But I bet if that happened in real life,
you'd be like, "You're tripping,
Melissa." I'm like, "No, I'm standing."
I don't know what you're talking about.
I don't know what that means.
My favorite My favorite impression to do
has always been Owen Wilson's. Owen
Wilson's my favorite.
[applause]
I
I think he'd be like, "Oh, you know
what? He always says the word heart in
all his films, you know, follow your
heart. Listen to your heart. Yeah. It
knows the way. Listen to your heart.
Yeah. Wow. Wow. Wow. Yeah. Wow.
I think [cheering] I think he'd be the
best yoga teacher cuz his voice is so
soothing, you know. Just now mountain
pose. Yeah. And now proud warrior. Gosh,
man. This pose reminds me of Shanghai
New I did with Jackie Chan. He was the
best. Yeah. Yeah.
Anyway, good class. [laughter]
[applause]
OH, THANKS. THAT'S YOU GUYS ARE TOO
NICE. AH, THANKS. You know, the only
person that I don't like, I'm sorry to
say this. I'm not a Christiana fan. I'm
done. Stop it, Christina. Stop adding
the letter
[screaming]
in the lyrics when it's not written in
there. Why are you reading it, you big
dumb? Stop it. I blame her kindergarten
teacher cuz he taught her the alphabet.
You know, if she never learned the
alphabet, she would never learn the
letter O. But I imagine her as a kid
practicing the alphabet around the
house, just A B C D E F G H I J K L M N
O Whoa.
Oh, [screaming]
THAT'S MY FAVORITE LETTER. SHUT UP. GET
YOUR ROOM. [screaming] GET OUT OF HERE.
YOU'RE GROUNDED. NO MORE CHEERIOS FOR
YOU. GET in there. Thanks, guys.
>> It's great to be here. I'd like to play
a song for you. Um,
this song is called [music] A World on
Fire.
This next song is uh a little bit
longer. Um,
[music]
it's about how sad I am and I'm really
sad and it's [music] called sad.
It's about all the sad things I see in
the world, guys. [music]
I met a homeless man named Rich.
[music]
Isn't that terrible? Oh, I saw a flyer
for a lost [singing] dog and the dog
didn't have any legs. I saw a [music]
diabetic kid. Yeah, trickor treating.
I saw a giraffe that had a small neck
that was sad or a deer. I saw
[singing and music] an old man get hit
by a train.
He didn't [singing] see it in the
pouring rain.
He didn't hear me. Shall look out for
the train
[music] cuz I didn't say anything.
I just thought to myself, "Ooh, this is
going to be sad." [music]
And it was.
I'm a genius.
>> [music]
>> I saw a man with only one [singing] eye
[music]
in a 3D movie. I saw a little boy drop
his ice cream cone directly on his
mother's corpse. I saw a kitten stuck in
a tree. [music] Then the kitten jumped
off and he hung itself. I saw a boy who
had red hair.
[music]
I went to a store looking for something
[music and singing] to buy, but they
only sold paintings of the same sad guy.
No, wait. This store sells mirrors.
[singing]
See what I did there? Let's rock. No.
[music]
The world's so sad. Montreal.
pain, starvation, AIDS, you know, but I
got to remember there's good things
about it, too.
Like the fact that none of that's
happening to me. Yes.
Still, though, it's hard not to be sad
about it. How do y'all do it? [music]
I've been telling Yeah, I know. I've
been telling you guys depressingly
depressingly sad things this whole song.
You haven't been sad at all. You've been
happy. No, you've been laughing. That's
it. Laughter, it's the key to
everything. [music] It's the way to
solve all the sadness in the world. I
mean, not for the people that are
actually sad, but the people like us
that got to [\h__\h] deal with them all
the time.
Being a comedian isn't being an
insensitive prick, capitalizing on the
most anim animalistic impulses of the
public. It's being a hero. The world's
not sad. [music] The world's funny. Yay,
I'm a sociopath. Thank you very much.
[cheering]
>> [applause]
>> Uh, thank you so much. You guys have
been so lovely. It's it's great to be
here. I have one last song for you. I
moved to uh Hollywood recently from
Boston. That's where I grew up. And I
had sort of heard about these um wild
sort of party nights that would happen
in Hollywood. I didn't think they were
true uh until I moved there and I
started having them myself. Anyway, this
is a song about a night that happened a
few weeks ago. It's called uh What Did I
Do Last Night?
Yeah, that's it. Crank that. [music]
Hey,
what did I do last night? [music]
[music]
I CRIED MYSELF TO SLEEP. Thank you very
much. Good night.
[music]
>> Hi everybody. That's my new funny walk.
NO TIME WASTED. YOU'RE LAUGHING AS I'M
WALKING OUT. HILARIOUS WALK-ON.
WHO ELSE DOES THAT? NOBODY because it's
embarrassing. Hi. How do I look? I've
lost weight. What do you think? How am I
looking? [cheering] Thank you.
[applause] Thank you. I'm extremely ill.
Thanks for clapping. Appreciate that.
Lost 12 lbs since lunch. Happy now?
The doctors say I'm not going to make it
career-wise. Now, why would the doctors
weigh in about my career during a
routine physical exam? I mean, yes, I
know I need more network and less cable,
but please, I'm here for a routine.
Okay, they did draw my blood and uh they
did a whole show business career panel
on me and uh they said my cholesterol is
good, but I'm low on buzz.
[laughter]
Why did I go to that direction?
Actually, there's a lot of buzz around
me, but uh they believe it's tonitis.
I'm a uh comedy veteran. I've been doing
comedy for over 28 years, which means
I've been doing it for 30.
I was in Atlanta, Georgia, and I uh I
misread a sign in the parking garage. I
I thought the sign said, "Please pay
uninformed cashier." [laughter] But
that's not what it said. It play it said
please pay uniform cashier which I
thought was still confusing. I don't
know what what kind of a uniform they
have like a tie made out of coins. What
do they but I thought it'd be a great
attraction if a parking garage did have
an uninformed cashier. Wouldn't that be
great? People would come from miles
around just to park there and they go up
to the booth. How much do I owe you? I
don't know. I really
have no idea. But you work here. Not
informed about my job. Should I stick it
in the slot? Oh, there's a [\h__\h] AND AND
THINGS OF THAT NATURE. EVERYBODY.
YES. CLAP BECAUSE IT FEELS GOOD JUST TO
SHAKE IT UP. [applause]
Just to get the old blood flowing.
Look at that walk. Look at Nobody walks
around the stage aimlessly like me. Has
anyone seen that great character that
Jimmy Fallon does? The obsequious late
night TV talk show host. Has anyone seen
that? Have you seen [cheering] it?
Here's my impression of Jimmy Fallon
interviewing Stalin.
>> Stalin, so great. Thanks for coming on
the show, Stalin. Big fan. Stalin,
I I heard you kill 30 million people.
That's crazy.
Would you like to play charades?
[laughter]
After these messages, Jimmy will play
Twister with Stalin.
Speaking of evil, vicious dictators, and
I mean Jimmy Fallon, Switcheroo,
I [clears throat]
Oh god, my own uh my own over-the-top
performance is bothering me.
[laughter] I am still obsessed with
Hitler. I uh I'm Jewish and I and I am
obsessed with Hitler. I have a Hitler
Google alert.
He's not getting a jump on me next time.
I have a key word, Blitzkrieg.
Do you know Hitler used to refer to his
enemies as haters?
>> Call me later on that joke. It's very
funny if you think about it.
In Israel about a year ago, they tried
to pass a law that made it uh illegal to
refer to the Holocaust inappropriately.
I don't know if they ever passed the law
because I don't research my jokes. I
just hope they stay the same. But if
they pass that law, everybody in Israel
will be in jail. Jews have to refer to
Hitler. I refer to Hitler and the
Holocaust four or five times a day. I go
to the airport, the flight's late. What
is this, a Holocaust?
I've spoken to the Holocaust survivors
and they have told me that uh references
to the Holocaust on a scale of one to
the Holocaust are one. Okay, they know
what happened. Me saying it is not going
to trigger anything for them. Oh, thanks
for reminding me. [laughter]
I get very dizzy when I uh um I get very
nauseous easily. That's why I can't uh
take a helicopter ride. I can't do it.
That's the only thing that kept me off
of Seal Team 6. [laughter]
Also, I can't swim. That beside that's
the two things that kept me off of Seal
Team Six. The elite fighting team FROM
AMERICA.
READ A PAPER. [laughter] ALSO, I don't
like to go into buildings when I don't
know what's happening inside. Oh my god.
Osama bin Laden's in there. Why would we
go in? I think let's stay out here. It
sounds like a better idea. I I forgot my
helmet in THE HELICOPTER. FOLKS, THAT
WAS SUPPOSED TO BE A CLOSING JOKE. It
didn't. IT CERTAINLY DIDN'T LAND the way
I hoped it would land, BUT THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR EXPERIENCING IT. GOD BLESS
ALL OF YOU. PLEASE ENJOY MY HILARIOUS
WALK BACK.
[music]
>> HELLO, ladies and gentlemen. How are you
feeling?
>> Good. Excellent. I am feeling uh
healthy. Thank you for asking because
this is the year that I decided to buy a
juicer.
It's great though because I enjoy being
a guy who has a juicer cuz now I get to
be a guy who talks about his juicer to
strangers. I get to tell them how much
energy I have and how great I feel. And
they ask stupid questions like, "Why
don't you just buy juice? cuz I'm not a
peasant.
I have to go to the grocery store and
buy $40 worth of produce every day,
take it home and run it through my
juicer, and then drink a glass of money.
That's how I start
[applause]
every morning.
There is a bit of a learning curve when
you buy a juicer because the first thing
you have to figure out is what has juice
in it [laughter]
because a lot of things do not.
If you put a banana in a juicer, you get
nothing.
There is zero return on investment when
you juice a banana. [laughter]
All you've done is found a very loud way
to completely destroy a banana.
>> [laughter]
>> They do want you to juice carrots,
though. And I know this because on the
front of the box the juicer came in,
there was a picture of a glass of carrot
juice. And after juicing two carrots, I
learned that that glass must have
contained 40,000 carrots.
[applause]
There's also like no juice in a carrot.
You should just eat carrots. People have
been doing that for a long time.
It's been fine.
You can juice a whole bag of carrots and
you will get a glass of juice that is
that big and you can drink that and it
will give you energy. In fact, it will
give you just enough energy to clean
your juicer. [applause]
I made the mistake of going to see
animals at the zoo recently, which is a
dumb idea because it's over for the zoo.
There are way better ways to see
animals. You can name any animal.
There's a 12 disc Blu-ray set of videos
of that animal happy narrated by Morgan
Freeman. You don't have to go to a place
where it's being held hostage and watch
a kid try to feed it a balloon.
It's not fun. The zoo IS SUCH AN OLD
IDEA, RIGHT? IT WAS INVENTED like a
thousand years ago by rich sultans who
were like, "I'M TIRED OF MURDERING POOR
PEOPLE FOR FUN. [laughter]
Someone bring me a strange beast from a
wild land." And they left and they came
back and like, "Uh, we found this tall
horse with a long neck.
What do you think about it? Does it do
anything?" Well, it tries to run away
all the time. I think it hates it here.
It's probably cold. It was really warm
where we found it.
I don't care. I want it forever. Put it
in a box. It's mine. Go get me another
thing. And they came back like, "We
found this cat. It's really big. It's
got fur around its head. Can I pet it?"
No. It's really mean.
In fact, it killed most of us.
All right, fine. Put it in the box with
my neck horse. [laughter]
Uh, it's killing your neck horse.
Oh, we're learning different boxes for
my weird things. [laughter]
And then we just kept doing that.
[applause]
Thank you.
But it is amazing that the zoo is still
around and there are terrible zoos in
existence right now. The zoo I went to
was an outdoor zoo in Canada.
That shouldn't exist.
It was just a bunch of squares of
chainlink fence they put animals in.
They didn't even cut down trees. YOU
KNOW HOW WEIRD IT IS seeing a camel next
to an evergreen tree.
It really takes away from the
experience. Or I walk up to one of the
cages that just said tiger and then all
you could see was a forest. And I asked
an employee, I was like, "Is there a
tiger in there?" He was like, "I don't
know.
It's probably behind the trees.
Well, have you checked? I'm not going in
there.
Says there's a tiger.
The weirdest part about that zoo I went
to, though, was I went into the washroom
at the zoo and they had a baby change
table in the washroom, which is not that
weird, but on the outside of the baby
change table, they had an instruction
panel, but the instructions were only
written in braille,
which is kind of weird. Like I know
blind people have kids obviously, but
I'm guessing they have jumped the
difficult hurdle of learning to change
that diaper at home. They're not
learning that for the first time in the
washroom at the goddamn zoo.
This seems like a good place to get on
top of my life. It's not happening.
Even above that, it also raises THE
QUESTION, WHO BROUGHT A BLIND PERSON TO
THE ZOO?
You are such a dick. [laughter] What are
you going to do? WALK AROUND ALL DAY?
ARE YOU HAVING A GOOD TIME LOOKING AT
ANIMALS?
NO, NOT AT ALL. THAT'S THE ONE THING I
CAN NEVER DO.
My other senses are heightened though,
AND IT SMELLS LIKE [\h__\h] HERE, so
[cheering]
[applause]
much. THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>> I love your country. I really do. I come
to Canada like six times a year. And I
think my favorite thing about being an
American in Canada is that there is no
depth to how stupid you feel we are
capable of being. [cheering]
[applause]
Yeah.
I feel like every family every family
has at least one profoundly stupid
person in the family.
talk amongst yourselves.
Even really successful families, like
you ever meet a family where it's like a
doctor, married a lawyer, and they're
like, you know, our three kids went to
Harvard and Yale and Princeton. And
you're like, yeah, but you have four
kids.
[laughter]
Don't you have somebody that you call
like just to feel smarter? You don't
have somebody like that. like you're
having a really bad day. You're like,
"Oh man, today sucks. I'm gonna call my
cousin Brian." [cheering]
[laughter]
That's my That's not your cousin, Brian.
I'm talking about my cousin Brian. If
you guys were like, "I don't have a
cousin Brian." I was talking about my
cousin.
I called him I called him a few weeks
ago and I was like, "What's up?" And he
goes, "Just putting together a list of
the smartest animals." And I was like,
"Oh, yeah. Sure.
For your research, I get it." Yeah. He's
like, "I got it down to the top three
smartest animals. It's uh dolphins,
elephants, and wolves." And he goes,
"Which do you think is the smartest?"
And I was like, "Well, I mean, I don't
know about those. I just know that
humans,
we're the smartest animal of all. We're
the most sophisticated." And he said,
"What makes you say that?"
[laughter]
Um, highways.
open heart surgery [\h__\h] that dolphins
don't do. Are we really going to argue
this one out?
Plus, we have thumbs.
He's also one of these guys like if we
go out to eat, every time we go out to
eat, if I order first, if I go, "Yeah,
let me get the uh teriyak chicken,"
he'll be like, "Ah, man. That's what I
was going to get." You still can
because we're at a restaurant.
I didn't order the last one.
Yeah, but then we'll both be eating the
same thing. You know what I mean? No, I
don't know what you mean.
Cuz I'm eating it and then you're eating
it and it's weird. No, you're weird.
[laughter]
It's not weird at all. It's weird if I
go, "I'm going to propose to Christie."
And then you go, "I'm going to propose
to Christie, too." That's weird. Then we
have to have a conversation like what
are we going to eat at the wedding?
[laughter]
Teriyak chicken. I don't know.
People ask me all the time cuz I travel
so much. I travel almost every week and
people will ask me. They'll be like,
"Oh, is there something you observe like
about everybody? Like is there something
that stands out about everywhere?" You
know, and I think there is. I think
there's one singular observation and
that is that everybody just wants to
connect. It doesn't matter where you go
or what language you speak, people just
want to connect. And you know when you
have chemistry with somebody, you know,
if you're like, I want to hang out with
this person or I want to date this
person or I want to harness this person
to the bottom of my big rig and drive
them around for a while and bury them 18
miles west of Lake Worth. And when I
drive by, I'll get a boner. We all have
these thoughts, right? Everybody gets
murder boners, not just me.
Sometimes
there's nothing there. And people try to
force a connection. I think that's rude.
You know, like I was checking in at the
airport to come here and the lady behind
the counter goes, "Where are you going
today?" And I said, "Uh, Montreal." And
she goes, "Ah, I have family in
Vancouver." And I was like, [laughter]
"What a coincidence."
And she goes, "Yeah, they got a
furniture store." And I was like, "Ah,
I like to sit on furniture.
[cheering and applause]
We're two for two.
I have shoes on. Do you have shoes on?
Do you like to walk around? We should
party."
There's nothing there. Sometimes there's
nothing there. You're not supposed to
connect with everybody on the planet.
That would be an absurd notion. You
should embrace that. I've been doing
this. You should do this, too. Next time
you're at a bar or you're just out
walking around and somebody goes, "Hey,
man." Just go, "Nope.
No. I'm all friended up." And they'll be
like, "I just want to know what time it
is." And be like, "I only tell my
friends what time it is." Thank you guys
very much. You're a lot of fun.
[music]
Good evening everyone. Or as the French
say, good evening.
No, it's bonjour benu. Yes. Yes. I'm
learning. I'm trying to practice my
French. The most romantic language in
the world. I know why the accent is
romantic as well, but it is. It's funny
how every accent has its own connotation
to it. Speak with a French accent, you
are sexy.
How are you ladies?
And then there's some accents just have
no sex appeal to them at all. Like the
Russian accent.
There's nothing sexy about it.
Everything the Russians say sounds
dangerous and menacing.
Doesn't matter what they cuz they've got
that thing. Yes. I'm Russian. Go to kill
you, break you, destroy your family.
Like even if Russians say nice things,
it still sounds dangerous. They still
go, yes, fluffy rabbits and teddy bears.
AH,
WHAT?
It's like that weird thing like the
Russian accent is so And you know, like
the crazy thing about the Russians is
everyone in the world is afraid of them.
Everyone, no matter where you go in the
world, you know, the Russians are
frightening because they're the only
country that makes America think before
doing something.
Everywhere else in the world, America
acts when something happens. When Russia
does something, we we think about it.
Yeah. You saw the whole thing that
happened with that plane that was shot
down, the Malaysian flight, the
Ukrainian rebels shot the plane, the
plane came down, you know, America came
out. Barack Obama, he was there. He's
like, "We're going to we got to find out
uh who did this. We're going to come
down on them like a like an iron fist.
We're going to let them know what time
it is." I'm paraphrasing. Uh
and then and then everyone found out it
was the Russians that supplied the
Ukrainian rebels with the missile that
shot down the plane. And then all of a
sudden, Obama was like, "But uh uh let's
not rush to conclusions.
Let's take our time and uh not point
fingers, especially not at the Russians.
Uh I'm going home now. Thank you very
much." There's something about the
Russians. The Russians. The Russians.
You know what's weird is I find the
Russian accent frightening,
but not the Russian language.
That's the strangest thing ever. There's
certain languages I find frightening.
There's certain accents that throw me
off, you know. For instance, I find
Arabic frightening as a language, you
know, it just has that thing in ital,
but that could be saying anything.
We're talking about Candy Crush.
But it's because we've watched all those
movies, all those TV shows. But every
time you see Arabic, some bad [\h__\h] goes
down.
It's never something cool or sexy, you
know? It's never like
it's never that.
So the language is frightening, but
Russian, for some reason, I don't find
frightening at all. Yeah. I don't I I
realize this. I was walking through the
streets of New York and there's a
Russian guy. He was walking next to me
and he happened to be on the phone,
right? And sounded like he was setting
up a drug deal. And so this guy is
walking next to me and he's talking and
he switched from Russian, he switched
from English, the English Russian accent
into Russian and it went from fear to no
fear. It was the strangest thing ever.
He was on the phone and he was like,
"Yeah, no Vlad, don't worry. The guys go
to bed at 3:00. Okay, you meet them, you
tell me. After that, you got the
package, we call. Don't No, don't worry.
Vlad, no. Listen. Blood. Blood. Blood.
And it was the craziest thing ever. He
went from like international criminal to
immigrant. IT WAS THE WEIRDEST THING.
Like I had no fear [applause] at all.
I'M NOT AFRAID of the Russian language.
Just the accent. In fact, to me, the
Russian language just sounds like
someone's playing a vinyl backwards.
That's all I hear. It sounds like
someone took a DJ of English and they
were just there like, "Yeah, yeah." He's
just like, "Yes, yes, we got to find.
Don't worry, Vlad. The guys got to be
there at 3:00." Okay. Yeah. Yeah. Bring
the package. Don't worry about that.
After that, you fine. You give me the
call. Okay. No. No. Vlad.
bit Russian. That's what I'm hearing
in my head.
[applause]
And if there's any Russian people here
tonight, I'm joking.
Please, I don't want to have issues
after this show. Walking out of the
theater. Hey, film guy.
Why you don't come DJ here?
Wiki Wiki, do it again.
Oh, you guys are fantastic, man. Thanks
for coming out tonight. We're going to
have an amazing amazing evening.
>> That's exciting. Yeah. I have a three
and a half-year-old. I had a daughter
when I was 44. Yeah.
Uh-huh. [applause]
Which is weird because I'm 38 now. And
um
No, her name is um Ava Ray Economous.
I've already explained to her that the
economous is silent and um
it's hard to pick a name. Like I wanted
to name her Emmy because I I've always
wanted an Emmy. And um
but when we were trying to pick her
middle name, it was like everybody was
giving a suggestion. So someone said,
"What about Lily?" And I'm like, "No,
that's like a pole answer. Absolutely
not." And someone said, "What about
Marie?" And I'm like my mother's like,
"That's so Catholic." like, "Oh."
And so my my daughter's father's mother
said, "Well, what about um Gina?" And
everyone's like, "That's so pretty." And
I'm like, "Hello, Ava Gina is not going
to be my daughter's name." No,
you know, we'll be like the
christristening and the ministry will be
like, "A vagina, what?"
And you know, she'd be like a rebel at
16. It's pronounced a vagina.
Do not rub me the wrong way. Anyway, I
um
wrong. Wrong. A little bit wrong.
Because I was so young when I had my
baby, I had like a million sonograms
taken. So, I started my own website, My
Tubes. And um
it's sort of bizarre though because she
loves candy and she's constantly taking
her clothes off and she goes up and like
dances to people like a little call
girl. She's like got any candy?
Candy? Like stop it.
It's kind of perfect that I have a three
and a half-year-old because I'm like
basically permenopausal. So, we're like
perfect companions. We both cry
uncontrollably for no reason. We love
candy and we enjoy battery operated
toys. So,
[applause]
I was reading her Fifty Shades of Gray
and um
no, it's the Canadian version 50 Shades
of A. It's the same story, but everyone
says sorry right afterwards. And
that is the most unrealistic books I've
ever seen. Three volumes of sex, not
one. Bladder infection. Fiction. Okay.
Fiction.
Seriously, she should be on an IV of
cranberry juice by the second chapter.
Just like
so. My mother is like basically she's
going deaf and Ava came up to me and she
goes, "Mommy,
is it vagina or pagina?"
And my mother screams from the bedroom,
"It's in Saskatchewan."
Totally ridiculous. Um,
so I had my heart broken recently and I
started to listen to Adele on my tripod
and um,
does she have the saddest voice in the
entire world? And and the weirdest thing
is she has like the voice of an angel,
but she sounds like Snookie when she
talks. Have you ever seen her? She like
I don't know how she would ever get
First of all, I played someone like you
so many times in a row. The couple below
me broke up and um
newlyweds. So sad, but
it is it's so depressing. How does she
ever get through recording? Uh can you
play that back for me? The sound
engineer killed himself. Adele, we
cannot.
Um so my little my little baby girl um I
just realized it was a 14-year-old and
I've said vagina 50 times, but um you
don't know what that is yet. No. Okay. I
don't want to know. I don't want to
know.
I don't want to know it. Anyway,
I was trying to think of something and
it's too dirty to say in my head. I
[clears throat] I love these women who
have like, have you seen the women with
the double strollers, the twins, and
then they have the third child stroller
underneath, which should just basically
be shaped like a therapist chair
because, you know, they've forgotten
that they even have that child.
That child has had Loblaw's bags thrown
on its head.
It has been staring at baby bum its
entire existence. It's just [snorts]
so Ava is having a complete meltdown the
other day and she's just like crying
hysterically and like in this totally
humiliating way and um all of a sudden
she's crying and and she you know they
they're able to like stand up and like
throw themselves down on the ground and
then get back up again like like anyway.
So I said, "Ava, you have two choices.
you can either stop crying and have a
popsicle, good motivation, or um you can
just go to bed right now. And she goes,
"Is there a third choice?"
People say very strange things to me
because I've obviously had my daughter
older. So, I was in the park and um this
woman comes up to me and she goes, "Um,
are you the lady who play on Sabrina the
Teenage Witch?
And I go I go, "Thank you. All right,
nice plug." And I go, "Um, yes, I am."
She goes, "You are my most favorite
character. I love this program so much.
Is this your grandchild?" And I'm like,
I go, "No, no, but I'm glad that people
on your planet enjoyed it wherever
you're from."
So I go home and I tell my sister, I go
I tell her what happened. She goes, "Oh
my god, did you slap her?" I'm like,
"No, I felt that was a bad choice."
Really, I just said to her, you know,
you got to let that stuff go. Just
forget about it. I just I went home. I
called immigration. I haven't seen her
since. And um that's how it's got to
work. Thank you. [applause]
Yeah.
Canada.
I I almost didn't come.
Be real with you. I'm I'm scared to
leave America. And you know, you leave
America now, they might not let you back
in.
You got to leave America the same way
you do a nightclub when you stepping out
to smoke a cigarette. You got to go to
customs and talk to the bouncer real
quick. Hey man, you going to be here
when I get back? I'm going to Canada
real quick to make a phone call.
I'll be right back. Here's the problem
with immigration.
Like first and foremost, you shouldn't
have to learn the language of the place
you choose to live. I think that's
highly overrated. Talking to people is a
stressful experience.
And it's better when you don't
understand. It's better. I try to fake
it every day. I try to fake not
understanding strangers. I don't want to
talk.
Hey, do you know which way to go? I
don't
cuz that's the thing. We demand that
people learn the language. That's what
they say. You need to learn the
language. If you're going to live here,
you need to learn the language. Learn
the language. Why? To talk to who? All
we do is ignore each other. All social
media has done is made us less social.
You want to talk to people and they
should learn the language when you walk
every day. You walk past fluent speaking
people who speak the same language as
you and you don't say a damn thing to
them cuz you rather mind your damn
business. That's how we live now. People
get on the elevator. Do you talk to
them? No. You can't even make friends
for 11 seconds.
11 seconds. That's all you have to do is
fake being interested in another human
being. And you can't do it. You press
your button and you stare at the wall
like a drone.
So why should we put that burden on
immigrants? Why should immigrants have
to learn the language? As soon as they
learn the language, ain't nobody going
to talk to the ass. They going to get on
the elevator and go, "Hello, I KNOW THE
LANGUAGE. SHUT YOUR ASS up and hit the
button." that
doesn't make sense. [applause]
But here's the problem to me. I feel
like if you the only people who should
have to learn the language is if you
work a job that's life or death. And
that's where the problem lies in
immigration for me. I have a foreign
doctor. He's fluent in English, which is
beautiful. The dude fluent does his job
beautifully. But the problem in America
is that they teach people English, but
they never teach them proper inflection.
I got a doctor that gives me bad news in
a good news tone and it's stressful
cuz he never learned how to properly say
bad stuff. My doctor comes we are
looking at your blood work the
abnormalities with the cholesterol if
YOU'RE NOT CAREFUL HEART ATTACK. I GO
WAIT a minute
that that's not how you say heart
attack. That is not how you say heart
attack. Heart attack is not a tiptoe
word. Heart attack is a downhill.
There's only three or four tiptoe words
in the English language as it is. Is woo
weam and like that's it.
Heart attack is not one of them. Talking
with some of my little cousins.
They got me back playing video games
again. I went back started back playing
Street Fighter.
Street Fighter. That's my game, man.
Street Fighter. If you know, if you
don't remember this video game, Street
Fighter is a video game where the basic
premise of the game is where two
strangers show up in a public place and
whoop each other's ass.
That's it. That's the entire game. One
dude walks up to another dude, hey, meet
me at the fish market during normal
business hours
and I will beat your ass.
That's the best part of Street Fighter
is that there's people in the background
shopping, acting like a ass whooping is
not occurring right in front of them.
It's two grown men in a fish market
throwing fireballs at each other.
Hadukan. Hadukan. And right behind him,
it's a dude. Yeah. Let me get some crab
legs.
And I take some of the snapper. Yeah.
Hooking.
Yeah. Box it up to go. I'm going to take
that to go. They throwing them
fireballs. Yes.
Best part of Street Fighter is that the
police never show up.
Nobody snitches during Street Fighter.
First of all, if you call 911, would
they would they even believe the
fireball call?
911? What's your emergency? Yeah. Uh
y'all need to get down here. Uh
is is uh two white people throwing
fireballs at each other.
Sir, this line is for emergencies only.
What you think a fireball is,
sir? We need a real emergency. Okay. Uh,
there's a black person here and they're
just reading on a bench.
[applause]
>> Thank you, guys. Uh, how you doing,
brown guys? Look at you, huh?
>> How's it going?
>> You guys, uh, you guys got the sale on
the shitty shoes.
>> What do you have in slippers? You have
two for one.
>> Are you guys twins?
>> Brothers. You're brothers. You do look
like twins. So,
>> but I mean, not identical, but very
close.
>> Same mother.
>> Who's older? Same mother.
>> Yeah. Good.
>> Different father.
>> Same father.
>> Yes. Good. Good. Who Who's older out of
you two?
>> Me.
>> You. How old are you?
>> 27.
>> 27. 27.
The same age as my career. 27.
What's your name?
>> Nash.
>> Nash Pinder.
>> Nash Pinder. There you go. That's H.
Everybody was like Nash.
>> Pinder. [laughter]
And you got the flowers on your head,
sweetheart. You look like a [\h__\h]
Snapchat.
Look like a
[applause]
>> It's her fault. I DIDN'T WANT TO WEAR
THEM. I did not want to wear them. She
made it for you. You still wore them?
>> She made it for me.
>> She looks amazing.
>> Yeah, she does.
>> Well, it'd be funny if her if she just
went and then like a dog face came out
like just like on.
It's a Snapchat reference for the older
folks. You have kids? Do you have kids,
ma'am? How many kids do you have? Two.
What do you got?
>> Boy and a girl. Which one do you like
better?
>> Boy or the girl?
>> I like them both.
>> You like them both? Uh, that that's not
really the question. That's not a
Listen, you you know that you have a
favorite. It's human nature to like
liking one of your kids more than the
other is literally the difference
between running and walking. You know
that, right? Like let me give an
example. You and your man, you're
sitting in the living room. You're
watching TV and all of a sudden you hear
somebody fall down the stairs,
right?
You're sitting all of a sudden you hear,
[screaming] "Oh my god, who is it? It's
me." Oh my god. Right. Okay. So, you're
sitting there. All of a sudden, you hear
Oh my god. WHO IS IT? IT'S ME. OH, for
[\h__\h] sakes.
That's all I'm trying to find out. Which
one would you run for? That's all I'm
asking.
It's the boy, isn't it?
It's always that way. You know, mama's
boy and daddy's little girl. I have a
daughter. I like her. She's um she's all
about daddy, which is great with me
because I'm daddy, you know. I think our
parents were the last great generation
of parents. If you think about it, they
knew how to control us. Think about when
you were growing up. There wasn't one
second, especially immigrant parents,
cuz immigrant parents are mad all the
time. I don't know what they're mad at,
but whenever they talk to you, they're
never like, "Isn't it a great move that
we left India and came to here?" You
know, [laughter] it's always like,
"Don't do that. LOOK AT ME. DO YOUR
HOMEWORK, make pee,
but we our parents controlled us. We
never and not for one second on any day
did I ever control my parents. And then
when I was having my daughter, I was
like, I'm going to do the same thing. My
do nobody's going to I'm going to
control my kids. And then when I had my
daughter, I realized I don't know how to
control somebody cuz I only know how to
be controlled.
And now my daughter owns my ass. SHE
GETS AWAY WITH I DON'T KNOW. SHE JEDI
mind tricks me, dude. She's They're
smart. Especially little girls. Little
boys kind of idiots. But um little girls
smart, sharp like that. Okay, I'll give
you an example how she Jedi mind trick
me. The other day she's at my house. I I
put dinner out for her on the table and
I go, "Baby, eat your dinner. I'm going
to go feed the dog." So I go I put her
food. I go to feed the dog. I come back
to the kitchen. My daughter's gone and
her food is there. And I'm like, "Where
the hell did she go?" And I can hear her
upstairs in her room. So, I go upstairs
to her room and she's playing and I go,
"Hey, you didn't finish your food." She
goes, "Sh,
this is a library."
And I'm so stupid. I went, "Oh, I'm
sorry.
They're smarter than us. They know how
to They get away with things now. We
never got away with things growing up."
like my my uh [clears throat] she was
lying on her bed. My daughter's lying in
her bed watching uh Frozen.
I've never actually watched this movie,
but Disney's smart. They put these songs
in their movies that the kids love and
you don't you don't need to watch the
movie. The songs are playing. They're
getting into your head. You don't even
know they're sitting in there. They just
sit there dormant.
Then they manifest themselves whenever
they need to. You don't even know the
songs are in there. I'm in traffic the
other day. This dude cuts me off. I lose
my temper. I GO, "YOU SON OF [screaming]
A BITCH." MY BROTHER JUST LOOKS AT ME
AND GOES, "DUDE, let it go.
[applause]
Let it go."
So anyway, my daughter's lying on her
bed while I'm watching Frozen on her
iPad. And I'm one of those dads who's
very excited. I'm always excited when I
see my daughter. I don't want to be a
cool dad. I don't want to be the dad
that's like, "Hey, uh, so listen, why
don't we have a conversation?"
>> No, she's a child and I'm very childish,
so it works out really well. So, I burst
into her room. First of all, it's my
house. I'll burst into whatever room I
want. Second of all, she's 5 and a half.
She's not going to be doing anything
weird, so we're good. So, I burst in her
room AND I GO, "BABY."
AND I GUESS it startled her.
But she didn't react like a 5-year-old.
She didn't react. She reacted like a
woman.
She got angry.
It wasn't like it was like this.
Without using any words, she went, "DO
YOU NOT SEE WHAT I'M DOING?"
And she got so angry that it made me
laugh.
And the more I laughed, the angrier she
got. Like a real woman.
Next time your woman's yelling at you, I
dare you to laugh.
Just they get worse. WHAT ARE YOU
LAUGHING AT? I DON'T KNOW.
But this is awesome cuz my happiness is
making you angrier.
And I'd start laughing. The more I would
laugh, the more angry she would get. And
the more angry she would get, the more I
would laugh until she was JUST FINALLY
LIKE, "DADDY, STOP IT." AND I GO, "I
CAN'T. YOU NEED TO BREAK THIS CHAIN."
And then I started thinking about it.
There wasn't one single time in my
entire life, even at 46 years old, that
I could have said to my dad, "Sh,
that would not have ended well ever."
Imagine being 5 years old. Me being 5
years old, sitting in the living room
watching TV, and my dad walks in, "Son,"
and I go, "Shh,
you don't sush me.
I'LL THROW THE TV AT YOU."
This was 1975 when TVs weighed 1,800 lb.
When it was more than just a TV, it was
a TV. It was a speaker system. It was a
shelving unit. It was a turntable on
top. It had an eighttrack player,
cassette deck. It held records, phone
books. It had a doily that ran across
the top with a vase with plastic flowers
in them.
[applause]
Those
plastic flowers were the best thing ever
invented in the 70s. You know,
sweetheart, you're wearing them on your
head.
Thank you, man. Trying to get it
together, man. I'm trying to lose
weight, man. I'm 37. My body's past
warranty.
Trying to lose weight. I'm I'm closed
for renovations. That's what I tell
women.
You want to go on a date? Nope. We had
to shut it down for a couple months.
Come back in December. It'll look nice.
We going to put it in a six-pack. It's
going to look nice.
Try to lose weight. Lose weight is one
of the most expensive things you can
ever do. Like to eat healthy. It costs
money. They don't tell you that. I had a
$8 smoothie. How the How would Why?
It's fruit and ice in the cup. How is
this $8 damn smoothie so expensive? I'm
surprised rappers don't talk about them
in their songs.
I see rappers now. I ain't impressed
with your jewelry. I want to see you
pull some kale out in the club. Do that.
That's how I know you got money.
We drinking kale, [\h__\h] We got
kale.
You some naked chick covered in soy
milk. It's just drizzling down.
My uncle got the solution though. My
uncle. You want to lose weight, boy?
What you need? You need to get you a
woman that can cook. You need a woman
that can cook, boy. That's what you
need. My My uncle one of them old black
men. He can't talk without wobbling and
doing that. You need a woman that's
going to get in that kitchen and throw
down for you. And to me, it's not that
important if a woman can cook or not at
this point in time in society. If you
can't cook, it's fine. Can you read?
Let's read a cookbook. Let's figure it
out.
As long as you bring something else to
the table, we'll get by. It's fine. But
my uncle won't let it go. My uncle,
look, ain't nothing wrong with a woman
having a job. But I'm telling you, when
I was your age, I love coming home to a
hot meal on my table. Yeah, I bet you
did love coming home to a hot meal. You
was dating in the 60s. You couldn't eat
nowhere in public.
That was your only chance at a safe
meal.
Spent all day doing cardio running from
white folks. Yes, you need a nice meal
at the house. I don't have to live how
you live. We got desegregation and
Chipotle. It's good times for me.
I'm chilling.
I know it's a lot of racial tension in
this world, man. And and that's it that
disappoints me that we live in these
times, you know, but I've seen I've seen
glimpses of what we could be in a
society. I know what we're capable of.
So when I see black white division, I
want to stay positive and knowing that
sooner or later it'll all work itself
out cuz I've seen it. I went to a black
history museum. I had a white tour guide
I don't even think you understand how
amazing that is. I went to a black
history museum and it was a white dude
walking US AROUND TELLING ME ABOUT
MATCHA AND HE was good.
He knew ALL THE FACTS. IT'S NOT LIKE HE
was glazing over stuff like, "Yeah, you
know, some stuff happened here. Come on
down. Look at Michael Jackson. Look at
this though.
This dude planted his feet and was
spitting the facts. And if you look over
here, this exhibit, boom, boom, boom,
boom, boom. I couldn't do nothing but
like respect the man. You're a white
dude working at a black history museum.
I respect you cuz I know that job
interview was a [\h__\h] Oh my god.
How many extra questions did he have to
answer? You white working at If you
black and old, you want to work at a
civil rights or black history museum.
That's easy. You just walk in. Ain't no
job interview. You just That's me on the
picture right there.
I'm going to go take my lunch break.
But if you white and working at a black
history museum, you know they was asking
that dude all kinds of extra questions
in the job interview. Stuff ain't got
nothing to do with black history. Uh we
look at your application. Everything
looks good. Uh last question. Uh at what
temperature do you deep fry catfish?
The the bigger question though is would
you even would you want a black tour
guide if you went to a black history
museum? White people, would you want a
black dude taking you around? I mean, it
might be more authentic, but you just
got to know you risking some stuff cuz
that brother might have a nervous
breakdown near mid tour.
You don't understand. A black history
museum is emotionally is a dark place to
go and you got a black dude taking you
around. He might have flashbacks in the
middle of the tour and just cuss out
everybody. Is that fair to you? Okay,
everybody, if you could just look over
here, this next exhibit, this is a 18th
century plantation home. And next to it,
that's the slave quarters. And that's
WHERE YOU MOTHERS KEPT MY PEOPLE.
Get your ass out my museum, cracker. And
it's just people crying in the lobby.
That's not fun.
It's tough times, man. It don't matter
how you feel about race relations in
this country. You can't tell me
something something is wrong. I don't
know if they doing it in Canada, but in
America, man, they got black people
blocking the freeway. They so
frustrated. And even if you don't agree
with that, you just got to acknowledge
something is wrong. If that's the the
the idea you've worked your way down to
in form of protest.
That's that's insane. [applause]
I mean, think about that. We We live We
live in a world now where black people
on the freeway is a legit reason for
being late to work.
You literally could just walk in your
job tomorrow. Sorry, I was late. There
was some negroes on the freeway. I
couldn't get past them. It was just
crazy. Couldn't swerve. It was all four
lanes.
They was on the freeway.
You know, it was the first white person
to use that as an excuse. When black
folks first started blocking the
freeway, you know, his boss didn't
believe him. That dude got fired.
Turner, YOU'RE LATE AGAIN. WHAT'S YOUR
EXCUSE THIS TIME? UH, LISTEN. You not
going to believe this, sir. But there
negroes on the freeway.
Don't nobody believe that, Turner. Get
your ass out of here. You're fired. You
son of a [\h__\h]
That's not even the worst part. Worst
part is that dude got fired and then he
went to his next job and now he had to
put down reason for leaving on the on
the job application.
You in a job interview, you got to
explain why you was late at the last
job. I'm noticing your paperwork here.
It says that uh you was late a lot at
your last job. You want to explain to me
why you were late? Ah, [groaning]
you're not going to believe this.
But there's negroes on the freeway.
I'm sorry. What did you say? It was
black people blocking the freeway. Okay.
And how did you handle that situation?
Well, you know, there's a lot of
different ways I could have handled it.
But I figured the best thing to do is to
sit there and be inconvenience and just
reflect upon the society that we now
live in that leads people to think that
that's the only option. That means the
system is broken.
That's a very good point. [applause]
You know what? You're hired.
Welcome to the Black History Museum.
I got to go, man. Thank y'all.